<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chasepd's blog - security, technology, and other stuff on chasepd</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in chasepd's blog - security, technology, and other stuff on chasepd</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chasepd.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leveraging AI Coding Tools for Security Code Review and Whitebox Penetration Testing</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/ai-tools-for-code-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/ai-tools-for-code-review/</guid><description>Introduction AI coding tools have fundamentally changed how developers write code, but their impact on security engineering workflows is still being explored. As someone who spends significant time reviewing code for vulnerabilities and conducting whitebox penetration tests, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that tools like Cursor can significantly enhance both the speed and thoroughness of security assessments.
This post covers practical strategies for integrating AI coding assistants into security code review and whitebox penetration testing workflows, based on real-world experience using these tools in production environments.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - RustyKey (Hard) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-rustykey-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-rustykey-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: RustyKey
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Hard
Release Date: 2025
Tech Stack: REDACTED Skills Learned: REDACTED
We start this box with creds: rr.parker / 8#t5HE8L!W3A
Nmap scan:
└─$ nmap -oN nmapscan -A rustykey.htb Starting Nmap 7.95 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2025-07-07 21:12 MDT Nmap scan report for rustykey.htb (10.129.25.190) Host is up (0.065s latency). Not shown: 988 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 53/tcp open domain Simple DNS Plus 88/tcp open kerberos-sec Microsoft Windows Kerberos (server time: 2025-07-08 11:12:37Z) 135/tcp open msrpc Microsoft Windows RPC 139/tcp open netbios-ssn Microsoft Windows netbios-ssn 389/tcp open ldap Microsoft Windows Active Directory LDAP (Domain: rustykey.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box - Chemistry (Easy) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-chemistry-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-chemistry-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: Chemistry
Listed Difficulty Rating: Easy
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Easy
Release Date: 2024 Tech Stack: Pymatgen CIF Parser, sqlite, aiohttp
Skills Learned: Default credentials, code injection, exploiting CVEs
Recon Initial nmap scan:
└─$ nmap -oN nmapscan -A chemistry Starting Nmap 7.95 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2025-07-06 21:37 MDT Nmap scan report for chemistry (10.129.231.170) Host is up (0.065s latency). Not shown: 998 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Voleur (Medium) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-voleur-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-voleur-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: Voleur
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Medium-Hard
Release Date: 2025
Tech Stack: REDACTED Skills Learned: REDACTED
On this box we start with credentials, which is becoming increasingly common on HTB:
As is common in real life Windows pentests, you will start the Voleur box with credentials for the following account: ryan.naylor / HollowOct31Nyt
Initial nmap scan:
└─$ nmap -oN nmapscan -A voleur Starting Nmap 7.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box - VulnCicada (Medium) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-vulncicada-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-vulncicada-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: VulnCicada
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Medium-Hard (mostly due to flaky and complicated exploit) Release Date: 2025 (Formerly from Vulnlab, acquired by Hack the Box)
Tech Stack: Kerberos, NFS, Active Directory, Active Directory Certificate Services Skills Learned: NFS enumeration, Active Directory enumeration, ADCS exploits
Recon To start, add some hostnames to /etc/hosts/ to make referencing the box easier. I always add boxname as well as boxname.</description></item><item><title>Hackerbox 0110 - Synth</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/hackerbox-0110-synth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/hackerbox-0110-synth/</guid><description>I open-sourced some alternate code for Hackerbox 0110. This converts the Synthesizer from the project into a game where the objective is to keep the ball in the circular screen for as long as possible.
Unfortunately, I tried to prototype a 3D printed case for it, but ended up killing the screen on it while attempting to put on the case before I got a picture of the game actually running.</description></item><item><title>Enumerating Windows Machines For Fun And Legal Profit Part 2</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum-part-2/</guid><description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re conducting penetration testing or participating in Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions, one of the most critical phases is enumeration.
This is part two of a two part series on Windows enumeration. For the first part, see https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/.
Impacket: Deep Protocol Interaction While NetExec provides broad coverage, Impacket offers deep, protocol-specific interaction capabilities. Think of Impacket as a specialized toolkit where each tool is designed for precise, targeted enumeration of specific Windows services and protocols.</description></item><item><title>Enumerating Windows Machines For Fun And Legal Profit Part 1</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/</guid><description>This should probably go without saying, but this should only be used on machines you have authorization to test. Doing this against stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t have permission to is likely illegal. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m not a lawyer, but I&amp;rsquo;m not responsible if you do something life-altering. Don&amp;rsquo;t be stupid. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re conducting penetration testing or participating in Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions, one of the most critical phases is enumeration. Think of enumeration as digital reconnaissance—you&amp;rsquo;re gathering intelligence about your target to understand its structure, services, and potential vulnerabilities before attempting any exploitation.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box - UnderPass (Easy) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-underpass-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-underpass-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: Underpass
Listed Difficulty Rating: Easy
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Easy
Release Date: 2024
Tech Stack: SNMP, Daloradius, Mosh
Skills Learned: SNMP enumeration, open-source software recon, mosh, sudo abuse
Recon To start, add some hostnames to /etc/hosts/ to make referencing the box easier. I always add boxname as well as boxname.htb to start with.
Next, we run an nmap scan to get some basic intel on the machine.</description></item><item><title>About chasepd - security engineer and tinkerer</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/about/</guid><description>Somehow, you’ve found the digital home of Chase Davies, or chasepd.
This site is a personal blog and project space for sharing thoughts, tutorials, and creative work. I write Hack The Box writeups when I feel so inclined, and otherwise ramble about topics in the hopes that it might be of help to someone at some point. Or because I feel like writing about them.
Not that I talk about my employer much (or at all) on here, but my views don&amp;rsquo;t represent my employer etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box - Mirai (Easy) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-mirai-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-mirai-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: Mirai
Listed Difficulty Rating: Easy
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Very Easy
Release Date: 2017 Tech Stack: Pi-hole, SSH, DNS
Skills Learned: Default credentials, sudo abuse, file recovery via strings
Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s get started by adding some hostnames for the box for easier use. I always add boxname as well as boxname.htb to start with.
Next, we run an nmap scan to get a basic topography of what is going on on the box.</description></item></channel></rss>