<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on chasepd</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/categories/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on chasepd</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chasepd.github.io/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack The Box - RustyKey (Hard) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-rustykey-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-rustykey-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: RustyKey
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Medium-Hard
Release Date: 2025
Tech Stack: REDACTED Skills Learned: REDACTED
We start this box with creds: rr.parker / 8#t5HE8L!W3A
Nmap scan:
└─$ nmap -oN nmapscan -A rustykey.htb Starting Nmap 7.95 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2025-07-07 21:12 MDT Nmap scan report for rustykey.htb (10.129.25.190) Host is up (0.065s latency). Not shown: 988 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 53/tcp open domain Simple DNS Plus 88/tcp open kerberos-sec Microsoft Windows Kerberos (server time: 2025-07-08 11:12:37Z) 135/tcp open msrpc Microsoft Windows RPC 139/tcp open netbios-ssn Microsoft Windows netbios-ssn 389/tcp open ldap Microsoft Windows Active Directory LDAP (Domain: rustykey.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Voleur (Medium) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-voleur-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-voleur-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: Voleur
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Medium-Hard
Release Date: 2025
Tech Stack: REDACTED Skills Learned: REDACTED
On this box we start with credentials, which is becoming increasingly common on HTB:
As is common in real life Windows pentests, you will start the Voleur box with credentials for the following account: ryan.naylor / HollowOct31Nyt
Initial nmap scan:
└─$ nmap -oN nmapscan -A voleur Starting Nmap 7.</description></item><item><title>Hack the Box - VulnCicada (Medium) Walkthrough</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-vulncicada-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/htb-vulncicada-walkthrough/</guid><description>Box Info Box Name: VulnCicada
Listed Difficulty Rating: Medium
chasepd&amp;rsquo;s Difficulty Rating: Medium-Hard (mostly due to flaky and complicated exploit) Release Date: 2025 (Formerly from Vulnlab, acquired by Hack the Box)
Tech Stack: Kerberos, NFS, Active Directory, Active Directory Certificate Services Skills Learned: NFS enumeration, Active Directory enumeration, ADCS exploits
Recon To start, add some hostnames to /etc/hosts/ to make referencing the box easier. I always add boxname as well as boxname.</description></item><item><title>Enumerating Windows Machines For Fun And Legal Profit Part 2</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum-part-2/</guid><description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re conducting penetration testing or participating in Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions, one of the most critical phases is enumeration.
This is part two of a two part series on Windows enumeration. For the first part, see https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/.
Impacket: Deep Protocol Interaction While NetExec provides broad coverage, Impacket offers deep, protocol-specific interaction capabilities. Think of Impacket as a specialized toolkit where each tool is designed for precise, targeted enumeration of specific Windows services and protocols.</description></item><item><title>Enumerating Windows Machines For Fun And Legal Profit Part 1</title><link>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chasepd.github.io/posts/tools-for-windows-enum/</guid><description>This should probably go without saying, but this should only be used on machines you have authorization to test. Doing this against stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t have permission to is likely illegal. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m not a lawyer, but I&amp;rsquo;m not responsible if you do something life-altering. Don&amp;rsquo;t be stupid. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re conducting penetration testing or participating in Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions, one of the most critical phases is enumeration. Think of enumeration as digital reconnaissance—you&amp;rsquo;re gathering intelligence about your target to understand its structure, services, and potential vulnerabilities before attempting any exploitation.</description></item></channel></rss>